<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Schachte&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://schachte.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Schachte&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Ryan Schachte</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 20:22:24 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://schachte.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Hugo Commands</title>
      <link>https://schachte.github.io/2020/12/21/hugo_cmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 20:22:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schachte.github.io/2020/12/21/hugo_cmd/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Commands Installing hugo
brew install hugo New site
hugo new site mysite Building the code
hugo server -t your-theme Viewing the site locally
hugo server Adding submodule to public directory
 Make sure you have at least one commit on the main branch on the target repo before running this  git submodule add -b main YOUR_REPO_URL.git public Creating a deployment script
#!/bin/sh  # If a command fails then the deploy stops set -e printf &amp;#34;\033[0;32mDeploying updates to GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burning Subtitles Into Video Files with FFMPEG</title>
      <link>https://schachte.github.io/2020/12/21/2020-12-21-burning-subtitles-into-vids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schachte.github.io/2020/12/21/2020-12-21-burning-subtitles-into-vids/</guid>
      <description>There are several recommendations for burning subtitles into video files on different operating systems such as Handbrake and VLC. Unfortunately, these programs fall short when offering customizability such as positioning and size, transformations and edits.
Aegisub and FFMPEG combined together can help achieve this with ease in less than 5 minutes. This article will walk through how to set that up and get started burning subtitles into your video files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Deployments With Docker, Elastic Beanstalk and Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://schachte.github.io/2020/12/20/2020-12-20-aws-and-github-automated-deployments-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schachte.github.io/2020/12/20/2020-12-20-aws-and-github-automated-deployments-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Requirements  NodeJS (https://nodejs.org) - If you decide to follow-along  Generate A Sample Application To Deploy  We are going to be auto-generating a &amp;ldquo;dummy&amp;rdquo; application to represent what we want to host. For this use-case, we will be using create-react-app. This is not required, as is simply just a simple use-case for generating a dummy application with unit tests. Feel free to use something like Java, Ruby, etc. If that is your language of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Indexes &amp; Performance Simplified</title>
      <link>https://schachte.github.io/2020/07/26/2020-06-01-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schachte.github.io/2020/07/26/2020-06-01-databases/</guid>
      <description>In this video, I dive into databases, indexes and performance. These are all very important things to know when dealing with modern web applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sliding Window - Algorithmic Mental Models</title>
      <link>https://schachte.github.io/2019/06/23/2020-05-20-sliding-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schachte.github.io/2019/06/23/2020-05-20-sliding-window/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the thought process and mental models of Sliding Window, a popular algorithmic method for optimizing your code!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>